# **ZACH MASON**

**Z**zacharycmason@gmail.com **②** zaturnvalley.github.io/Portfolio **↓** 425.458.8992 **۞** zaturnvalley

# SUMMARY

I'm a full-stack, front-end leaning web developer with a Masters in Teaching. I am experienced with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MEAN stack (MongoDB, Express, Angular.js, Node.js), SQL, Ruby on Rails, Marketo, C#, and more. When I'm not coding, I'm producing music, traveling, and spending time with my dog and wife.

# **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Python, C# FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES: AngularJS, Rails, Express.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, jQuery, ReactJS, MeteorJS DATABASES: SQL, MongoDB OTHER SKILLS: Research, Collaboration, Leadership, Conflict Resolution, Teaching

# **EDUCATION**

#### **General Assembly**

Web Development Immersive 2016

•Built projects utilizing Javascript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Angular.js, SQL, Ruby on Rails.

# **Seattle University**

Masters in Teaching 2013

• Endorsements: History & Social Studies.

# **Pepperdine University**

B.A. History 2008

• Studied abroad in Heidelberg, Germany (2005 - 2006)

# **EMPLOYMENT**

### Catalysis, Jr. Front End Developer, Seattle, WA

Jan 2017 - Oct 2017

• Developed responsive Microsoft emails and landing webpages using ExactTarget, Marketo and technologies such as HTML, CSS, AmpScript, and JavaScript. Deployed collaborative quick iterations of builds involving: QAing, unit testing, and debugging in an agile environment in order to deliver marketing promotions and newsletters. Built C# apps as growth goals.

# General Assembly Immersive, Web Developer, Seattle, WA

Iul 2016 - Oct 2016

• 12 week immersive course with 480 hours of instruction, 5 sprint development projects in an agile environment. Utilized HTML, CSS, Javascript, MEAN stack (MongoDB, Express, Angular.js, Node.js), SQL, Ruby on Rails.

#### Kent School District, Social Studies Teacher, Kent, WA

Aug 2015 - Jun 2016

- Taught 9th grade Contemporary World History & 11th grade US History
- Cycle of Inquiry Growth Goal met by 90% of students; writing with evidence
- Collaborated with PLC to design unit lesson plans and assessments; analyzed data.

#### Bellevue School District, Substitute Teacher, Bellevue, WA

Aug 2013 - Jun 2015

• Instructed 4-12th grade History, English, Humanities, Government, & Economics.

## Huntington Learning Center, Tutor, Bothell, WA

Feb 2011 - Dec 2011

• Taught K-12th grade students. Trained new tutors and monitored student progress.

#### EFL Institute, English Teacher, Daegu, South Korea

Jul 2009 - Jul 2010

• Managed and taught K-8th grade Korean students in reading, writing, & English.

# **PROJECTS**

#### Consignment Shop App

Aug 2017

A C# App that can be used by consignment shops to run their business. Includes list of vendor, items, commission, etc.

#### Marvel Hero Explorer

Mar 2017 - Apr 2017

A Windows 10 App Marvel Hero App using C#, XAML, and the Marvel Hero API

Portfolio

Sep 2016

My personal portfolio. Contains links to all projects, personal bio, resume, and contact. Link: https://zaturnvalley.github.io/Portfolio/

Oct 2016 Indecisive

A MEAN stack app that helps users make decisions based on averaged data. Uses Chart.js for visualizations, MongoDB, Express.js, Angular.js, and Node.js. Link: http://indecisivelife.herokuapp.com/

Game Ranker Aug 2016

A full stack app that allows you to search a video game API and rate / review games.

Used HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, SQL, Sequelize, Express, AJAX, Bcrypt, EJS & EJS Layouts, Passport. Link: http://gameranker.herokuapp.com/

Sep 2016 Chat Emoji

A full-stack Ruby on Rails web socket app designed by a team of 4 collaboratively. The app's focus centered around helping users to find and live chat with like-minded patrons. Technologies Used: Ruby on Rails + Active Record, Web Socket / Action Cable, User Authentication, HTML / CSS, Postgres, CoffeeScript, Wireframes, Emoji Picker Gem, and Bcrypt.

Resume Wordifier Sep 2016

A sprint development fullstack collaborative app completed during a 24 hour hackathon. Wordifier takes any job description and builds a cloud map of the main keywords on the page. Technologies used: MongoDb, Express.js, Angular.js, Node.js, Mongoose, JWT.

### Game of War + 52 Card Pick Up

Aug 2016

Utilized HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery to create a game of war and 52 card pick up simulation. Link: https://zaturnvalley.github.io/GameOfWar/